Look, there's a symptom that is coming out like a water in your stomach.
Yes, faeces and water. It is getting to two years now - 22 months.
Since after the surgery, I did...
Don't worry. That is what I am seeing - the symptoms coming out of your stomach -
both the water and the...
Father! Thank You, Jesus!
What do you think is the cause?
I did an intestinal surgery in February, 2015.
They said some parts of my intestine were rotten.
So, they had to cut off some parts of the intestine.
Then, after stitching it, the thing burst.
A wrong operation.
Yes, it then resulted to a fistula.
I said there is a wrong operation. After praying for you, go back.
I will tell you to go back to the doctor; they will cover it back.
If they cover the face now, there is a wrong thing they have cut in your stomach.
And you carry pads anywhere you go.
Thank You, Jesus!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering Prayer And Prophecy In Jesus' Name
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
The footage you are about to watch is of a sensitive nature.
Although it may not be suitable for all viewers, it is for the glory of God.
Good Morning, Church!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Kate Chimezie.
By my side is my son, Clifford Chimezie.
My brother.
My daughter, Chidubem Chimezie and my son Oluchukwu Chimezie.
Thank you.
Kate Chimezie & Family
Healing Testimony
So we would like to hear your wonderful testimony to the glory of God
The problem that brought me to The SCOAN was the problem of enterocutanea fistula
as a result of a surgery I went through in February 2015
whereby the doctors did a procedure called exploratory laparotomy of the right hemicolectomy.
The problem started just a day like that. I woke up. I was having pain in my abdominal wall.
I went to the hospital. They sent me for a scan.
After the scan, when the result came, they said, "Immediate surgery".
So I went to the first hospital. They rejected me. They were afraid that I was not going to make it.
They took me to another hospital.
I was even wheeled to the hospital because I was only - I was not stable.
I was really bad so the doctors now took me to the theatre.
When they opened me up, they saw that almost all the intestine was ruptured.
So one of the doctors, the surgeon said, "We are going to close her up; she cannot make it".
One of them said, "No! Let's try".
I heard them calling me, "Madam, do you believe in the power of God?"
I said, "Yes, I do".
So they said, "Okay, they are proceeding" They proceeded and did the surgery.
And after that they removed most of my intestine; it was cut off.
And they sutured it. So after this suturing, I think most of it busted.
A complication like that then resulted in the enterocutanea fistula
whereby there's a leakage of faecal matter from my intestine to the abdominal wall,
which means that I cannot really do so many things because of it.
I always pad my stomach all the time. I cannot walk very well.
I cannot stand up to drink water. I cannot sit down to eat.
I can only lie down to eat or lie down to drink water.
Each time, I would always put my hand in my stomach to remove all the faecal things
because as at that time, I was not able to pass stool.
Okay, you mean to say, madam, that the faeces would come out through your stomach?
Yes, all the things I ate, the faeces,
the faecal matter was coming out from my intestine to my abdominal wall.
I was always removing it three to four times a day. Then we would put plaster on it again.
Anything I ate, I would feel the movement and it made me very uncomfortable.
I was not able to do many things, even on the bed.
I couldn't go anywhere - my business, everything was closed down.
And the pain that goes with it, is like.. inexplicable.
Okay, so just to be very clear, madam, the pictures we are seeing here show
how these faeces would come from your stomach region
as opposed to coming through the normal passage after the complications of this surgery.
Yes, the faeces was now coming out from my stomach - the water, everything.
What was supposed to go as waste through the rectum was all coming out from my stomach.
And you said during this period, you could not eat normally, you would have to lie down,
even just to take a small drop of wáter and you were even unable to take a bath, is that right?
Yes, during this period I didn't really eat.
I ate once in a while. Even that still leaked. I took little water.
And before I took them, I didn't like sitting while eating. If I wanted to put something in my mouth,
I would have to go to my bed and lie on my back.
I couldn't even lie on my side or on my tummy.
I would only lie on my back. I would just lie down like that and drink wáter.
All through this period, I never had my bath for one day - normal bathing like a human being.
It was only cleaning. I would just clean up, day by day, from morning till night,
365 days times three. So I never had a normal bath.
So people of God, we can understand the severity of the condition that our mother was in.
She just recounted now how for three whole years, she was facing this situation
after the problem with the surgery. The faeces would pass through her stomach.
She couldn't take a bath. She couldn't eat normally.
She had to lie down, just to take a little bit of wáter and as she ate, she would feel the food
pass through her stomach until it formed faeces and then she had to take it out through her stomach.
This was the critical condition that she was in as a result of that complication in surgery.
Madam, after this surgery, medically, what did the doctors advise you about
how they could try and resolve this issue?
When I went from one hospital to the other, seeking second opinions from different medical practitioners,
what they told me was that, "Madam, you should be happy and thank your God
that you survived this initial surgery. Don't ever attempt going for any medical procedure again
because it will be worse or you may not even make it".
So you were facing the prospect of living like this for the rest of your life as a result..
Now tell us - in the midst of this, where else did you go in search of a solution
when this situation was so critical?
When this situation persisted because they had also told me that the intestine -
the way it was - a lot of it had been cut.
I could not be able to lift so many things like lifting weights.
So from there, I was now going from one hospital to the other again going to churches.
Then one of the doctors told me that I should allow nature to take its course,
"Let the healing be a natural thing".
That I shouldn't go to do anything because of the danger of it.
So from there, I proceeded to so many churches.
Like I went to Abuja to one church.
When I went there, I had to pay money to see the man of God.
So when I got into his office, they were telling me that they had to calculate how old I was
so that the money - that's how they would know the exact amount I was going to pay.
I was also to pay their transport money from Abuja to Lagos, for the healing and deliverance, everything.
When they had calculated everything, the money was so much. So I said, "No".
When I was in the office, I saw the photograph of Prophet T.B. Joshua pasted in the office.
I said to myself, "Wow, this is our dear great prophet, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
So if his prophet is there, if his photograph is there, what am I doing?
And I know that at The SCOAN, no money is being paid
for any healing services rendered to human beings".
Kate Chimezie & Family
Healing Testimony
It was on these notes that I came back to Lagos and came to The SCOAN.
Okay, now we watched on the clip how this Word of prophecy came about.
Can you just recount to us that day.
What happened when you received that Word of prophecy?
When I came that day, I was privileged to meet with the man of God.
He came close to me and touched me.
He now prophesied and said, "There are symptoms coming out from your stomach".
He asked me, "What was the cause?" I said, "I don't know".
He said, "Wrong surgery". He asked me, "What surgery?"
I was trying to tell him. He said, "No, wrong surgery. Don't worry.
I'm going to pray for you and after the prayer, you go back and they will correct the mistake".
Hallelujah. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So tell us, after receiving this word of prophecy, what happened next?
When I received this prophecy - because initially, I had refused to go for any other surgery
because people were suggesting that I should go for surgery, go for other medical things.
I said, "No. I'm not ready" because previously, I've had other surgeries - like four surgeries in my life.
So I didn't really - in fact, I was very bad, even my photos show that I was not stable
to withstand another surgery. So I didn´t want to go for any surgery.
But when I got here and the man of God now prophesied to me that after the prayer,
I was to go back to these medical practioners, for them to do "a correction".
He said, "A correction".
That was now what made me go back to the hospital.
When I got back to the hospital, the doctors told me on the day of the surgery
that they were going to do a colostomy for me.
I said, "Wow! Which one is colostomy again?" That they were going to put a colostomy bag for me.
A colostomy bag is something - it is a bag connected to the intestinal walls;
from the intestine to the outside abdominal wall, wherein all the faecal matter like faeces and water
would be stored on a daily basis and you would be emptying it like every four to five hours.
After like three to six months, I would go back, and they would remove the colostomy bag
and then restore everything.
I said, "No. That wasn't what my prophet said.
My prophet said that I was going for "a correction".
He said, "Ah!" The other asked, "Who are you?"
He asked, "Are you Emmanuel?" I said, "Yes".
He asked, "From where?". I said, "Synagogue Church Of All Nations. Prophet T.B. Joshua".
He said, "Oh, I know that radical prophet".
So that was the reaction of the doctor?
Yes, that was what they said.
So they said, "Ok".
They told us all the things we were going to get for the surgery. We bought so many things.
When I entered inside the theater, my children were outside
because that time I didn't know what was happening again.
They were always going outside to meet my children to go and buy this and that.
They were always buying, buying, buying.
When they had bought it, they would return it back and tell them, "We don't need it, we didn't use it.
Go and buy this one". They kept on buying and returning. My children were like, "Oh, what is happening?
For over six hours, she has been there.
Nobody is telling us anything - only buy and return. So what´s happening?"
That was how after like six hours, they woke me up and said, "Madam, we are taking you to your room".
I said, "Thank You, Jesus!" They then took me to my room.
On the following day, I was standing on my feet. I was walking.
Every tube that they had put on me - both in the mouth and nose, everything -
the following day, they removed everything.
On the third, fourth day, I was discharged from the hospital.
And here I am now. I am healed, I am fine, I am good.
I came here with my family to return honour and glory to whom honour is due, in the mighty name of Jesus.
I also thank our dear Prophet T.B. Joshua for what he has allowed God to use him to do
and also thank our mummy in the Lord, Evangelist Evelyn Joshua,
for her support all through this period and all the evangelists.
Now I can go to the toilet normally. I can walk around. I can move around.
I can lie anyhow. I can do anything.
Initially, I couldn't do anything. Anywhere I went, I had to pad myself.
I had to use cloth and tie myself with a belt. I couldn't move.
I could not do anything. I was not able to do anything.
Oh, my goodness! It is so much.
When during the first service this year January 2018, the man of God was declaring a new beginning,
I was saying, "New beginning? Look at how I am! How am I going to start a new beginning?"
I never knew it was coming so easily like that, so soon.
Wow, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Indeed, we can all see that our mother is fully, completely restored,
and we give all the glory to God Almighty for that prophetic word that gave her the assurance
that God Almighty would actually use the medical doctors to correct the wrong surgery
and restore her to the position to which God created her.
We give all the glory to God and madam, we can see a couple of pictures on the board,
apart from the ones we saw earlier.
Could you just describe to us what we are seeing on each of these pictures?
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Hey, these pictures here. Initially - that was then, not now.
Horrible!
This was my photo - what I was going through in my life during that period.
In those three years - 365 days times three.
So this was me. This was how the faecal matter was always coming out from my intestine.
I didn´t even eat anything, except bread, something that was hard so it could come out.
If not, it would just flow out.
Look at it here.
Look at how it was. This surface was always bloody 24/7.
Each time I opened it up, it was like they had just performed the surgery that same day.
Look at it here.
Each time, every like three to four hours, it was soaked already. It was leaking everywhere, is padded.
I always used cotton wool, gauze, antiseptic, cream.
I would then plaster it.
This was how I tied myself, even more than this.
Before, I couldn't move because the whole thing was always motion on the surface
and it was always very, very painful.
Here are just a few of all the things I used to use for dressing, my drugs.
This roller plaster, it lasted for like two days. This is just the 5 x 10 cm plaster that I used.
There are always 5 in this pack, and it lasted for 2 days. This cotton wool lasted for like three to four days.
Then the creams and all other drugs.
Besides, when I came to The SCOAN, I was addicted to this drug called Tramadol.
Everybody knows what Tramadol is.
I had been on that drug for almost seven years before I came
because I had had an injury on my leg, a broken ankle that I sustained through domestic violence.
So since then, I had been addicted to that drug because I was unable to do anything.
I couldn't stop that drug. I couldn't move.
I couldn't move my leg and everything.
But on one of the days, when dear prophet was ministering deliverance,
he just tapped my face.
He tapped me on the forehead and went because that time he was always preaching,
"That if you forget your drug, know that God has done it".
Each time I prayed, I would ask God, "Please make me forget my drugs".
And that day, lo and behold, after the tap, I went home. In the night, I didn´t feel pain.
In the morning when I woke up, I didn´t feel pain, I didn´t remember the Tramadol.
I didn´t take Tramadol and that was how the Tramadol episode left. It has been over for a year now.
Now there's no more Tramadol. Thank you.
Wow, let´s put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Now we would like to hear a quick word from your children. If we could hear from our brother here.
Just a quick word, what he can say as a son to see his mother restored
after such a traumatic experience for the family.
My name is Clifford Chimezie.
My mom had been sick for three years, over three years. I think since February 2015.
It had been terrible since then.
Sometimes when I went out to have fun with my friends, I would remember that my mom was at home.
So we understand the emotion our brother is conveying.
If you put yourself in his position to see your own mother going through such suffering,
I'm very sure you would express similar emotions.
But we thank God today that that past pain has been replaced by perfect good health,
and we thank God that today, it's turned into a testimony.
So we give all the glory to God for what He has done in the life of this family.
Brother, you were saying how this really affected you as her son.
Okay.
I was the only one in the hospital.
Kate Chimezie & Family
Healing Testimony
At this point, we can really understand the emotions that are being conveyed by our brother.
Let's quickly hear from another one of the family members
as we give our brother a few moments to compose himself.
We can really feel what he is feeling as someone
that has seen his own mother nearly at the point of death to where God restored her.
Our brother, you are welcome.
Please introduce yourself and tell us what you can say concerning this wonderful testimony.
Hello everyone. My name is Oluchukwu Chimezie.
As you have seen my mom was sick for about 3 years.
It was troubling us for a while,
even though I wasn´t around when she did the first surgery.
They didn't tell me most of the things she was passing through.
They just wanted me to concentrate on my studies.
It was when I came back ending of 2016, I knew the gravity of what she was facing.
I tried to convince her to go for another surgery.
She refused. She was like, the doctors advised her against it.
If she did it, she was going to die.
Every time we went to the hospital, they kept on saying - they kept on giving excuses
that the reason why it had not healed was because of diabetes, high blood pressure, or low sugar.
They kept on coming up with different things, and we would say, "Okay. Let's change the routine.
The next six months you are going to eat this.
The next three months maybe you're going to be on total bed rest".
We just kept on changing (her routine) and nothing was changing.
Every time she would still come back. We would still buy plasters in bulk every month.
It was not like something that anyone should go through, any son should go through.
These things affected our lives in so many ways, even socially.
You would go out with your friends and you would think you're having fun.
Then it would dawn on you that someone was at home that needed help;
someone was not feeling fine.
Then, immediately, your mood would swing. You would start feeling bad.
You would not even concentrate again and you would want to get back home.
You see, Christmas, New Year celebrations, Easter -
I mean, those were for normal people, not for us. We didn't celebrate those holidays
because these people that have the luxury to do that, that have chosen to celebrate it...
When you see your mom when you get home, and you see her like that,
you would just feel bad.
Most of the time I ended up just going out. I would go out and have some drinks with friends,
just so that I could be calm and forget about what was going on.
I wouldn't think about it that much.
As I was saying, it's not something that someone should ever go through.
Can you just tell us as her son,
how do you feel now seeing her fully restored?
When you saw her come out of the operation and to see the changes in her life,
just tell us the celebration in the family since that wonderful encounter.
It was overwhelming because during the surgery, we saw them coming out
with this big bucket filled with blood - transparent buckets like this.
I mean, it was filled with blood and there was this thing moving around in it, floating.
I was thinking, "Hey, they put my mum's small intestine in there.
That she's not going to have any other option than to do the...
Maybe she would just be like that all her life".
I was later that everybody was like, "We need to know what they did.
What exactly did they do?" We found out that, "Hey, it's been closed. Everything is fine".
We were so happy. We were overwhelmed with joy!
And this was something that I thought would have a recovery time of like 3 months, 6 months.
In the next two days, I saw my mum walking around. I was like, "What happened? How come?"
Kate Chimezie & Family
Healing Testimony
Few days later, they discharged her.
I went back. I was like, "Are you people sure? You want this lady to go?"
They were like, "Yeah, she's fine. You can go. We've done everything".
I really...
You don't even understand how joyful I am just now, for what God has done in my life.
You see people everywhere.
Maybe you want to be like this person, "This person, I want his life". Or something like that.
And you don't know that the person might be going through serious depression.
What I was going through wasn't physical. You would see me. I would be smiling at you.
But inside, I was going through serious pain every day - every day of my life.
Basically, you would get people telling you in different ways, "I want to be like you"
and in my mind I would be like, "You don´t know what I'm passing through"
but I couldn't really tell them that.
The celebration has returned to the family and the family can now be happy -
truly, through this healing.
I'm really overjoyed. I can't even overemphasize.
You don't even know what's going through my mind just now.
Amen! Let´s put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We know there are no natural words to describe it, except to say, "Thank You, Jesus!"
And we know that our brother has really expressed that joy on behalf of the family.
Let's just hear a quick word from our sister as well.
My name is Chidubem Chimezie.
The problem that brought my mom to this church was the problem of fistula enterocutanea
This really affected her a lot and affected me a lot because I would be in school,
but most times, I would have to come home. It was just hard doing a lot of things
because she couldn't really do anything herself. So most times, I had to face school, face her.
Just mostly mental issues.
It really affected me schoolwise, physically, everything.
But I just thank God a lot that she's here, and she's healed right now. Thank You, God.
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We give all the glory to God Almighty.
We just want to hear a final word from our brother now.
I just want to thank God because till now, I cannot believe it.
I still go to her room in the morning to check if it is true.
During those days, I would dream that I was actually sewing up her stomach.
These days, I still did not believe it. Even tomorrow, I'm still going to go and check.
Because I am still in shock. I still cannot believe it yet.
I'm going to check tomorrow again. I need to be sure.
Because it was for three years - three very long years.
A professional doctor said that she was going to die.
When she went for the first surgery, I was the only one in the hospital.
How could a doctor come out to tell me that my mother was going to die?
Why?
But today she is alive, and fully restored in our midst.
Yes, she is fully restored. I think she´s getting to seven weeks recovery.
I don't know how that is possible. It is normally three months.
But after four weeks, she was fine - completely.
They discharged her after three days. She was completely fine after four weeks.
How? I do not know.
It is God. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So finally, brother, let's hear from you on behalf of the family.
What is your word of advice to our viewers all over the world and those present here today?
Ok. I'm actually not a member. I came because of the testimony.
It's a big one.
She watches Emmanuel TV so I just come across it, I watched it a little bit.
I saw the prophet talking.
But I did not like her seeing me when I was watching it so that she didn't push me into it.
So I usually hid it from her when I was watching Emmanuel TV.
My advice to everybody here is:
He is one of the few prophets in the country that actually speaks the good news.
Listen to him. Do not allow these words to be used against you on Judgment Day.
Listen to him. Don't just take these words, leave this place and forget about them.
She's a better person today because she listened to him. Forget about the sickness.
Please listen to him. I know what I'm saying.
I know what I heard. Just one minute ago, I know what I received. I know what I got.
Listen to him. Let it always be in your head.
Remember it. Let it always be in your mouth that you may speak it to the world.
Let it always be in your heart that you may attain eternal salvation. Thank you.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Thank You, Jesus.
Finally, we want to hear a final word of advice from you to our viewers,
with what Jesus has done for you, restoring you completely.
What is your word of advice and encouragement to our viewers all over the world
to cap off this wonderful testimony?
Good Morning, Church.
I'm still thanking God and thanking the God of Prophet T.B. Joshua
for all He has done in my life and my family.
I know this not going to be the end of my testimony.
So what I'm saying and advising the whole world and viewers, anywhere you are:
This Word - it is only the Word that can set you free.
The way he always talks about it, the way he stresses it.
He says, "Listen to it!"
It will slowly show you what to do, tell you what to do - at any time in your life, at any crossroad.
When you are with Him and He is with you, you don't have a problem.
He said that when Job was there and the permission was granted to the enemy to tempt Job,
he did so because God was holding Job's hand and at the end what happened?
Job was successful. He was victorious because God was with him.
When God of Prophet T.B. Joshua is with you, no matter what situation you find yourself in,
victory is sure, in Jesus' name.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We thank God for this wonderful testimony. We pray that God will give the grace to this family
to continue to make His Word the standard for their lives
and we know more wonderful testimonies are coming, in Jesus' name.
Amen. Thank You, Jesus, I'm healed.